### MAHESH MUPPASANI

### **Fullstack Software Engineer**

mahesh.muppasani007@gmail.com https://linkedin.com/in/mahesh-muppasani/ https://maheshmuppasani.vercel.app/ +1989491-1302

Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience in fullstack development, software design, requirements gathering and business automation. Recognized for exceptional contributions to customer experience and efficient management of business functions. Proficient in Node.js, React.js, Angular, PostgreSQL, MongoDB etc.

## **Work Experience**

#### Full Stack Engineer (Internship) | BigLynx Inc, Bellevue, WA, US

Jan 2024 - Nov 2024

- Integrated Dynamics 365 CRM with Node.js and Power BI for real-time dashboards, automating business reporting by 50% and cutting manual effort by 40%.
- Performed consistent maintanance, implemented redis caching, query optimization and developed stored procedures in PostgreSQL, optimizing system performance which resulted in an improved latency of 65%.
- Created a scalable e-commerce app with microservice architecture using PostgreSQL, Node.js, React.js and integrating payment gateways via Stripe, reducing API latency by 30% and supporting 99.9% uptime consistently.

#### IT Support Engineer (Part-time) | Central Michigan University, Mt.Pleasant, MI, US

Jan 2023 - Dec 2023

- Developed and provided operational support to the university's website cutting page latency by 60%, enhancing accessibility and scalability to handle over 10,000 concurrent users.
- Integrated Tableau UI into administrator dashboard for real-time visualization of student and semester enrollment trends, improving data accessibility, enabling data-driven decisions, and cutting reporting time by 30%.

### Software Engineer (Full-time) | Innova Solutions, Hyderabad, India

Aug 2021 - Dec 2022

- Leveraged Node.js, MongoDB, Apollo GraphQL and React.js to reduce 100% of manual work for processing supplementary product orders by developing a robust enterprise application for administrators.
- Developed a real-time inventory management interface with MVC design pattern, leveraging React Hooks (custom and generic) and Redux, cutting data inconsistencies by 100% and automating reporting process by 75%.
- The system drives operational excellence by automating order fulfillment, cutting processing time by 80%, optimizing inventory control, and reducing stock discrepancies by 35%.

#### Associate Software Engineer (Full-time) | Innova Solutions, Hyderabad, India

Dec 2019 - Aug 2021

- Developed an e-commerce platform for a leading pharmaceutical company, automating order processing, driving a 50% sales increase and boosting user experience by 70% leveraging Angular with GraphQL APIs.
- Rebuilt an inventory tracking app migrating from ASP.NET server pages to modern React with TypeScript, maintaining zero downtime, improving system performance by 75% and reduced latency by 60%.

# **Projects**

#### BigLynx CRM Portal | Node.js, PostgreSQL, Redis, React.js, Figma

Jan 2024 - Nov 2024

- Developed a customizable CRM portal using Node.js, PostgreSQL and Dynamics 365, enabling streamlined customer data management and workflow automation, improving system's efficiency by 30%.
- Designed and integrated Power BI dashboards to provide real-time insights on sales performance and customer trends, accelerating decision making by 45%.
- Optimized backend performance by effective coding standards, code refactoring, and implementing caching strategies using redis, resulting in a 65% improvement in response times and system reliability.

#### MH Fulfilment | Node.js, MongoDB, Apollo GraphQL, React.js, TypeScript

Aug 2021 - Dec 2022

• Developed a scalable administrator application for a leading pharmaceutical company streamlining Node.js with MongoDB, GraphQL schemas, and React.js, enabling efficient processing of 8,000+ customer orders per month.

• Streamlined order lifecycle processes leveraging microservice architecture with GraphQL schemas, Mongoose ORM, and MongoDB Atlas, resulting a 39% increase in average order volume through cross-team collaboration.

Nutrascriptives Direct | Node.js, JWT, Angular, Apollo Client, Semantic UI

Dec 2019 - Aug 2021

- Developed an innovative e-commerce app using Node.js, Angular, Semantic UI, GraphQL APIs and Figma, automating the ordering process, achieving 60% of automation while ensuring 100% order accuracy consistently.
- Contributed to an increase in sales revenue with an exceptional growth rate of 41%, significantly enhancing the user interface and experience.

## **Volunteer Experience**

#### Front End Panel Recruiter | Innova Solutions

Aug 2021 - Dec 2022

• Played a pivotal role in the recruitment process at Innova Solutions by taking over 100+ technical interviews as a front-end panel member, helping the firm to filter and onboard the applicants, resulting in 30% hiring efficiency.

### Technical Mentor - Web Development Training Program | Innova Solutions

Aug 2021 - Feb 2022

• Mentored a team of 5 trainees at Innova Solutions, teaching key front-end technologies such as JavaScript, React.js, Angular, and other frameworks. The team delivered three projects, boosting customer revenue by 29%.

#### **Core Skills**

C, C++, Node.js, Python, JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, HTML, CSS3, React.js, Redux.js, Vue.js, Angular, NgRx, RxJS, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Material-UI, Semantic UI, Webpack, Vite, Babel, REST API, GraphQL, Apollo Client, Apollo Server, Axios, Fetch API, Socket.IO, Express.js, Nodemon, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MSSQL, MariaDB, Sequelize, JWT, OAuth, Bcrypt, AuthO, Firebase Authentication, Jest, Git, GitLab, Responsive web design, Developer Tools, SignalR, Agile software development Lifecycle, SCRUM, Waterfall, UI/UX, Figma, data structures, application design, object-oriented design, Computer Science essentials, Algorithm design, Problem Solving

#### **Education**

Master of Science in Information Systems | GPA: 3.9/4.0

Jan 2023 - Dec 2024

Central Michigan University, MI, USA

Bachelor of Electronics and Communication Engineering | GPA: 3.6/4.0

Jul 2016 - May 2020

K L University, Andhra Pradesh, India

#### **Awards**

#### Best Intern of the Year | BigLynx Inc

Aug 2024

Won "Best Intern of the Year" award at BigLynx Inc. for outstanding contributions to the BigLynx CRM Portal, boosting client efficiency by 30% and improving system performance and decision-making.

#### **Customer Champion Award** | *Innova Solutions*

Oct 2021

Received the Customer Champion Award in recognition of exceptional contributions by guiding the team in completing 8 weeks of tickets in just 4 weeks and fostering customer satisfaction.